<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meta on mrnice.dev</title>
    <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in meta on mrnice.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 21:10:59 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build This Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-build-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 21:10:59 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-build-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting some questions as to how I made this blog. So I decided I&amp;rsquo;ll share all the little details so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to 🔍 look it up.
I&amp;rsquo;ll try to be as cross-platform as I can, but I did all of this on Ubuntu (via WSL).
 Create repositories on GitHub  GitHub Pages repository Blog content repository  Install Hugo Initialize blog content Connecting the blog repo to the Pages repo Connect to a custom domain  Buying and configuring a domain Configuring the CNAME Configuring the base URL SSL 🔐  Quality of life  Easy deployment  Other fun stuff you can do  🐣 Set up twitter cards 🖼 Add a logo 📊 Add Google Analytics 🎨 Add custom CSS files 📣 Add social links  Summary  Create repositories on GitHub GitHub Pages repository Like it says in GitHub&amp;rsquo;s guide, you need to create a repository with the name &amp;lt;your_username_here&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first Post</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>The blank page So many possibilities, but so much anxiety. How do I make this interesting? Who will even read this? Have I picked the best theme? What should my other posts be? How do I go forward from here? Is this for me, or for you?
Here&amp;rsquo;s a poem about it as well if you thought I wasn&amp;rsquo;t dramatic enough Beating the blank page / Alan j Wright A Battle-Cry for the Brave Young Writer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>