<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mrnice.dev</title>
    <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on mrnice.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 22:29:59 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mrnice.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GopherCon Israel 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/gophercon-israel-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 22:29:59 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/gophercon-israel-2024/</guid>
      <description>GopherCon Israel 2024! What a fun day.&#xA;Started by seeing lots of familiar faces! Miki Tebeka, Yarden Laifenfeld, Liri Sokol, Guy Brandwine, Itamar Knafo, Ran Bar-Zik and more. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun knowing people and saying hi to everyone, and meeting new people, too.&#xA;I arrived there and met some people from Orca Security (where I work right now). These are my raw notes from the event, not too much editing, mostly for my peeps from Orca&amp;rsquo;s Golang Guild.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book report: The Ideal Team Player</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/the-ideal-team-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 21:48:01 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/the-ideal-team-player/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR The three virtues Humility Hunger Smart Where&amp;rsquo;s the proof? Compared to Turn the Ship Around! The Goal The story Hiring &amp;amp; promoting Employee Development Trusted Advisors What about performance? Dollar-store psychology Conclusion Improve myself Improve my team Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve read The Ideal Team Player by Patrick Lencioni following Yoav Alon&amp;rsquo;s recommendation. I&amp;rsquo;ve read it on a train: best way to read books. You can&amp;rsquo;t do anything else, and your fellow passengers think you&amp;rsquo;re smart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevProd Adventure</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/devex-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 03:24:45 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/devex-adventure/</guid>
      <description>Context This is a presentation I gave at Angular Ventures in 2024. It&amp;rsquo;s about the new-ish and emerging concept of Developer Experience, and what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about it over the last year of doing it.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s a Reveal.js presentation, so you can view it in your browser on Desktop only. Use the arrow keys and Esc to navigate, and press s to see the speaker notes.&#xA;Presentation Developer Experience The adventure begins.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>בנינו כלי פנימי לצוותי הפיתוח שלנו, והלא ייאמן קרה: הם היו מרוצים</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-build-a-command-line-aka-cli-app-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 09:48:22 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-build-a-command-line-aka-cli-app-with-go/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Added a Now Page to my Hugo Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/added-a-now-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 18:34:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/added-a-now-page/</guid>
      <description>/now.&#xA;What&amp;rsquo;s a now page? Well, the person behind it, Derek Sivers, explains it best on his blog .&#xA;How to add a now page for Hugo Derek&amp;rsquo;s explanation doesn&amp;rsquo;t include how to do it with Hugo! Since some people might be interested in that, and it&amp;rsquo;s not 100% the same formula as adding a new post, here&amp;rsquo;s how:&#xA;hugo new now.md &amp;hellip;Wait, that&amp;rsquo;s it 😅. Just don&amp;rsquo;t write the posts/ you normally do when running hugo new.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shay Nehmad&#39;s Now page</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 17:42:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/now/</guid>
      <description>What Shay&amp;rsquo;s up to now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick script to refresh a Hugo Post Date</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/refresh-hugo-post-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 12:10:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/refresh-hugo-post-date/</guid>
      <description>I tend to go back to old, unpublished posts every now and restart my work on them. They&amp;rsquo;re just resting, hiding behind the -D flag of hugo server.&#xA;But when I want to publish said post, I want the date to be the current date, not the creation date. So I wrote a script to update the date of a post to the current date.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s the script in action:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding shorts to the blog</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/shorts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 19:31:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/shorts/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;m sick. Strep. Missed the Seder, as well.&#xA;Taking a few days off to recover, time to play around with the blog.&#xA;Why add shorts if you already have posts? Shorts are more than a tweet, less than a post.&#xA;Stream of consciousness notes that don&amp;rsquo;t merit a more dedicated write-up.&#xA;Inspired by Brandur Leach&amp;rsquo;s fragments in his beautiful corner of the web.&#xA;My hope is that this short-form, more than a tweet, less than a post format will help me publish more often.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>🎧🍏 AirPods (well, any bluetooth) alias for MacOS</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/airpods-alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 18:11:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/airpods-alias/</guid>
      <description>So, one early morning, and I’m just getting my coffee. For fun, let’s automate connecting to bluetooth AirPods without touching the mouse. Quick Google brings up blueutil, and a tiny bit of jq was all the glue needed:&#xA;brew install blueutil blueutil --connect $(blueutil --paired --format json-pretty | jq -r &amp;#34;.[] | select(.name | contains(\&amp;#34;Shay’s AirPods Pro\&amp;#34;)) | .address) The first time you run this, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to give the terminal permission to get access to bluetooth:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A few Go tools for production-level developer applications (Orca Meetup)</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/a-few-go-tools-for-production-level-developer-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 23:22:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/a-few-go-tools-for-production-level-developer-applications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Data-Intensive Applications: Flashcards for a Book Club</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/designing-data-intensive-applications-bookclub-flashcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 02:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/designing-data-intensive-applications-bookclub-flashcards/</guid>
      <description>How did we get here Back when I left Reco, my parting gift to everyone at the company was books 📚. At the time, these were books I haven&amp;rsquo;t read, but were recommended by the interwebz. The idea was to stay in touch with the team by gifting them good books and loaning them from time to time. That&amp;rsquo;s how I wrote a book report about &amp;ldquo;Turn the Ship Around&amp;rdquo;, for example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Checking out Advent of Cyber 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/advent-of-cyber-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:11:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/advent-of-cyber-2023/</guid>
      <description>To keep this spoiler-free, I&amp;rsquo;ll be redacting the flag. Whenever you see {{ .flag }} in the text, it means that I&amp;rsquo;ve redacted the flag.&#xA;Yes, this is go&amp;rsquo;s text/template syntax. It&amp;rsquo;s the best templating language on the planet.&#xA;Getting started The signup/login UX leaves something to be desired. You start off on the advent page, then sign up, and after the initial signup you are not redirected to the advent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to add a status page to your Hugo blog</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/statuspage-on-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 22:58:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/statuspage-on-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Shortest guide possible, let&amp;rsquo;s go ⚡️&#xA;Setting up a status page I recommend onlineornot.com.&#xA;Take your blog&amp;rsquo;s URL. For me, that&amp;rsquo;s https://mrnice.dev. Create a new check on that URL. Pick &amp;ldquo;Monitor a website&amp;rdquo;. Create a status page, and choose your subdomain. I went with mrnicedev ~&amp;gt; you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a URL like https://mrnicedev.onlineornot.com. You should get something that looks like this:&#xA;Adding the status page link to your blog We&amp;rsquo;ll do it from the config.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diagramming in Webflow with Mermaid.js 🧜‍♀️</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/mermaid-on-webflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 23:22:46 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/mermaid-on-webflow/</guid>
      <description>How to set up a Mermaid.js diagram on your Webflow site, the shortest guide possible:&#xA;Install Mermaid for a specific post Add an HTML Embed Code by clicking on this button:&#xA;Copy this HTML Embed Code snippet to the top of the post.&#xA;&amp;lt;script type=&amp;#34;module&amp;#34;&amp;gt; // Include mermaid.js import mermaid from &amp;#39;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/mermaid@10/dist/mermaid.esm.min.mjs&amp;#39;; // Initialize the Mermaid chart mermaid.initialize({ startOnLoad: true, // Apply the dark theme - replace with what you want.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is an API proxy?</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/what-is-an-api-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 23:22:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/what-is-an-api-proxy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in A11y: Trying Out Talon &amp; Cursorless, part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/trying-out-talon-and-cursorless-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 13:35:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/trying-out-talon-and-cursorless-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Everyone benefits from accessibility.&#xA;Accessible design improves access to information on the web for individuals with and without disabilities. Well-designed, accessible web sites expedite the delivery of information and services. Providing accessible websites and electronic documents allows a greater variety of consumers to obtain information regardless of their individual needs.&#xA;~From National DB&amp;rsquo;s accessibility toolkit&#xA;This post is a part of a series. Check out the previous posts for more context.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in A11y: Trying Out Talon &amp; Cursorless, part 0</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/trying-out-talon-and-cursorless-part-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 21:50:07 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/trying-out-talon-and-cursorless-part-0/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Shay, you mentioned some number of episodes ago that the army took your mouse for a while. What would you do if they took your keyboard, as well?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;This post is starting out by me typing it on my keyboard. However, if things go well, by the end of this post some part should be typed out with my voice.&#xA;Every part that is in between lines (like this one) is actually typed out with Cursorless and with my voice, not my keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>API Consumption Problems 101 - a hands-on guide</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/api-consumption-problems-101-a-hands-on-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 12:07:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/api-consumption-problems-101-a-hands-on-guide/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E for Engineering: From defense to IT | Better Tech Leadership interview</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/better-tech-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 12:07:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/better-tech-leadership/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning CSS #2: CSS Diner Writeup 🍱🥢</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/learning-css-with-css-battles-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 08:03:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/learning-css-with-css-battles-2/</guid>
      <description>Met up with Aviv Sarig to practice some CSS. I found CSS Diner and we went through it to hone our CSS selection skills.&#xA;Start with &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo;: why practice selectors? I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand why we need selectors in the first place. The answer is simple - to select specific elements in the DOM so we can style them the way we want.&#xA;I think that building good semantic HTML is the first step to writing good CSS, and that knowing how I&amp;rsquo;ll end up selecting elements will impact how I structure the HTML itself.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
