<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mrnice.dev</title>
    <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on mrnice.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 09:36:21 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mrnice.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimize your Hugo Blog With Unlighthouse</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/optimize-hugo-with-unlighthouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 09:36:21 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/optimize-hugo-with-unlighthouse/</guid>
      <description>Recently Google let me see the new Analytics dashboard (they moved from&amp;hellip; Something something analytics to something something Analytics 4). And one of they things I saw was that my blog&amp;rsquo;s performance was bad!
In general the blog&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure didn&amp;rsquo;t get much love since I opened it a few years ago, so a cleanup for performance and content is probably in order.
Get initial Lighthouse results What&amp;rsquo;s Lighthouse? It&amp;rsquo;s a tool that Google provides to measure the performance of your site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI-assisted API Design 🤖🧑‍🎨</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/ai-assisted-api-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 11:57:30 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/ai-assisted-api-design/</guid>
      <description>My experience working alongside ChatGPT to generate OpenAPI specs.
As part of a client job (as a newly-minted freelancer!) I got, I needed to design an API. I decided to write an OpenAPI spec. I&amp;rsquo;m so used to gRPC that looking at the OpenAPI JSONs and YAMLs doesn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;gel&amp;rdquo; well in my brain, but I do know the basics of API design. And, well&amp;hellip;
With that in mind, and since the project itself revolves around LLMs, I decided to write the spec together with ChatGPT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book report: Turn the Ship Around! A VP R&amp;D&#39;s Summary</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/turn-the-ship-around-a-vp-rnd-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 11:29:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/turn-the-ship-around-a-vp-rnd-summary/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve read Turn the Ship Around! by L. David Marquet following Anton Drukh&amp;rsquo;s recommendation.
This summary is mostly for me and for people I&amp;rsquo;ll refer it to - so it&amp;rsquo;s not the most friendly read. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t have time to read the book, this post can serve as a useful TL;DR for you. I highly recommend you do read it - it&amp;rsquo;s a great read and a short one, too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Flashcard Shortcode</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/hugo-flashcard-shortcode-for-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 20:46:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/hugo-flashcard-shortcode-for-study/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s a flashcard? Click here! It&amp;rsquo;s a card with a question on one side and the answer on the other. You can use it to study for a test or memorize notes from a book you&amp;rsquo;ve read. Cool! How do I get it for my Hugo site? Download these three files:
CSS JS HTML Shortcode And put them in the right places in your Hugo project. The JS and CSS files go in your static/js/flashcard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Battle #1 Writeup: Learning CSS</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/learning-css-with-css-battles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 11:35:20 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/learning-css-with-css-battles/</guid>
      <description>You might be asking yourself how did you get here? I know I&amp;rsquo;m sort of asking myself the same question: the TL;DR is I never stop learning, and right now I needed to learn some CSS for my job.
I&amp;rsquo;ve started learning CSS for real at work recently to be able to do full-stack E2E development. So far, CSS was a &amp;ldquo;hack it until it works&amp;rdquo; kind of thing for me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve never done it properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We gave a talk at GopherCon Israel 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/we-gave-a-talk-at-gophercon-israel-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 17:51:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/we-gave-a-talk-at-gophercon-israel-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use simple RSS feeds to monitor SaaS application in Slack - The shortest guide possible</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-use-simple-rss-feeds-to-monitor-saas-application-in-slack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 14:15:55 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-use-simple-rss-feeds-to-monitor-saas-application-in-slack/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cup O&#39; Go Episode 0: Premiere Episode, Upcoming 1.20 Release and Gophercons World Wide!</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/cup-o-go-episode-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 14:15:55 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/cup-o-go-episode-0/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build Your Team to Increase Velocity</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-build-your-team-to-increase-velocity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 11:01:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-build-your-team-to-increase-velocity/</guid>
      <description>As a manager, I felt the struggle of trying to balance the urgency of delivering new features with the importance of maintaining high code quality. That&amp;rsquo;s why I went together with a team lead from Reco - Michael Lantsman - to a great meetup at Riskified about this subject exactly. It had some great insights, so I&amp;rsquo;m sharing them here :)
After some food and beer, Shai Peretz gave a warm introduction, then Itay Waxman shared some practical strategies for fast delivery without creating tech debt, and finally we had a very insightful panel about team velocity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We gave a talk at the Go Israel November 2022 Meetup</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/go-israel-november-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 14:15:55 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/go-israel-november-meetup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up Backstage On K8s with Helm - part 1, set up for success</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-backstage-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 21:53:20 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-backstage-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I recently set up Backstage.io on our cluster. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t super-easy, so I decided to &amp;ldquo;go deep&amp;rdquo; and tried to make this a learning opportiunity.
I&amp;rsquo;m also definitely not a DevOps expert, so I had to learn some stuff myself along the way. Here&amp;rsquo;s my best approximation at a useful guide for anyone who&amp;rsquo;s going to walk the same path! Hopefully I can save you some time.
Part 1 In this part we&amp;rsquo;re going to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Before: Good Cross-functional Team/Bad Cross-functional Team</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/good-cross-functional-team-bad-cross-functional-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 23:52:52 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/good-cross-functional-team-bad-cross-functional-team/</guid>
      <description>News at Reco! Soon - exactly 1 next month from when I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog post - we&amp;rsquo;re rebuilding our R&amp;amp;D structure. Part of the change means that ownership of delivery is mostly on me: essentially updating my title to VP R&amp;amp;D (from VP of Engineering), temporarily. I say temporarily since I&amp;rsquo;m sure that we&amp;rsquo;ll change again and again. The exciting part is that we&amp;rsquo;re building a structure of 4 cross-functional teams, and growing the group members a lot faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerability Report: Are LucidCharts Safe When Shared to Confluence?</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/lucid-vuln-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 14:15:55 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/lucid-vuln-report/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrix 🤝 Reco R&amp;D meetup</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/astrix-reco-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 14:15:55 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/astrix-reco-meetup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Attended the Go Israel March 2022 Meetup</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/we-attended-the-go-israel-march-2022-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 22:29:06 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/we-attended-the-go-israel-march-2022-meetup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>print(&#39;Hello, World! We’re R&amp;D@RecoLabs.ai&#39;)</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/print-hello-world-were-recolabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 22:29:06 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/print-hello-world-were-recolabs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Built a Slack Bot for Valet Parking Services: 🅿️art 3 | The Data</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 20:04:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Part three of the joint project with my incredibly sharp wife, Olga!
This post is a part of a series, so [check out the entire series for context] (https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/slack/).
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into how we&amp;rsquo;ve implemented a Database in our application. The post starts with the design, then moves to implementation of DB connectivity, then the data models themselves, and finally some testing.
Upfront, we had to decide if we&amp;rsquo;ll choose a relational database or something else - and we decided to go relational.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Built a Slack Bot for Valet Parking Services: 🅿️art 2 | The Logic</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 12:23:06 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Part two of the joint project with my intelligent and brave wife, Olga!
This post is a part of a series, so [check out part 1 for context] (../building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp).
Warning: As our development of this project was a little &amp;ldquo;all over the place&amp;rdquo; as we try to fit it to our busy lives and the Holiday Season, the blog post is a little all over the place as well.
QoL improvements Slimming down the Docker Image size Adding a test endpoint to the server, to make sure it works Adding basic CI Setting up a local development environment Designing and Building the Bot&amp;rsquo;s Business Logic Let&amp;rsquo;s do some Product - designing the user flows Initial development - design, mocks, stubs Let&amp;rsquo;s do some Development - using Bolt Let&amp;rsquo;s get sidetracked - Web servers, web applications, and WSGI Next up QoL improvements Before moving on the the next big tasks, we wanted to do some small QoL improvements, which we introduced in 3 separate PRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Built a Slack Bot for Valet Parking Services: 🅿️art 1 | The Start</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 15:18:40 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp/</guid>
      <description>A joint project with my beautiful wife Olga! &amp;lt;3
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll go over how we built a Slack Bot that helped my company manage parking spots.
Table of Contents Requirements Why do this, the stupid reason Why do this, the real reason Planning Task Management Architecture Working Setting up a working environment Setting up GCP Developing an initial server Containerizing the server Deploying the app to the cloud Connecting the server to Slack What&amp;rsquo;s next?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foray Into Clojure, Part 2: Polymorphism, Recursion, Debugging, and Sesame Cake | 日々是好日</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-foray-into-clojure-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 08:32:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-foray-into-clojure-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;日々是好日&amp;rdquo; (Nichinichi kore kōnichi) means &amp;ldquo;Every day is a good day&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Try to spend every day meaningfully&amp;rdquo;.
This blog post continues directly from the previous one, so I&amp;rsquo;ll skip the intros. Go read that one for context. Let&amp;rsquo;s just jump into it!
Table of Contents
Runtime Polymorphism Using multi-arity functions Value-based polymorphism with defmulti Comparison to other languages Breaking down what the code means Open to extension Lazy Sequences iterate is also zero-based Standing on the shoulders of giants - using identity Sequence Comprehensions :when and other predefined keyword modifiers Creating Functions The let special form Function composition with comp Recursion Use comment loop?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
