<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mrnice.dev</title>
    <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on mrnice.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 14:15:55 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mrnice.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Astrix 🤝 Reco R&amp;D meetup</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/astrix-reco-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 14:15:55 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/astrix-reco-meetup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Attended the Go Israel March 2022 Meetup</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/we-attended-the-go-israel-march-2022-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 22:29:06 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/we-attended-the-go-israel-march-2022-meetup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>print(&#39;Hello, World! We’re R&amp;D@RecoLabs.ai&#39;)</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/print-hello-world-were-recolabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 22:29:06 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/print-hello-world-were-recolabs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Built a Slack Bot for Valet Parking Services: 🅿️art 3 | The Data</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 20:04:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Part three of the joint project with my incredibly sharp wife, Olga!
This post is a part of a series, so [check out the entire series for context] (https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/slack/).
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into how we&amp;rsquo;ve implemented a Database in our application. The post starts with the design, then moves to implementation of DB connectivity, then the data models themselves, and finally some testing.
Upfront, we had to decide if we&amp;rsquo;ll choose a relational database or something else - and we decided to go relational.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Built a Slack Bot for Valet Parking Services: 🅿️art 2 | The Logic</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 12:23:06 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Part two of the joint project with my intelligent and brave wife, Olga!
This post is a part of a series, so [check out part 1 for context] (../building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp).
Warning: As our development of this project was a little &amp;ldquo;all over the place&amp;rdquo; as we try to fit it to our busy lives and the Holiday Season, the blog post is a little all over the place as well.
QoL improvements Slimming down the Docker Image size Adding a test endpoint to the server, to make sure it works Adding basic CI Setting up a local development environment Designing and Building the Bot&amp;rsquo;s Business Logic Let&amp;rsquo;s do some Product - designing the user flows Initial development - design, mocks, stubs Let&amp;rsquo;s do some Development - using Bolt Let&amp;rsquo;s get sidetracked - Web servers, web applications, and WSGI Next up QoL improvements Before moving on the the next big tasks, we wanted to do some small QoL improvements, which we introduced in 3 separate PRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Built a Slack Bot for Valet Parking Services: 🅿️art 1 | The Start</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 15:18:40 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp/</guid>
      <description>A joint project with my beautiful wife Olga! &amp;lt;3
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll go over how we built a Slack Bot that helped my company manage parking spots.
Table of Contents Requirements Why do this, the stupid reason Why do this, the real reason Planning Task Management Architecture Working Setting up a working environment Setting up GCP Developing an initial server Containerizing the server Deploying the app to the cloud Connecting the server to Slack What&amp;rsquo;s next?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foray Into Clojure, Part 2: Polymorphism, Recursion, Debugging, and Sesame Cake | 日々是好日</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-foray-into-clojure-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 08:32:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-foray-into-clojure-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;日々是好日&amp;rdquo; (Nichinichi kore kōnichi) means &amp;ldquo;Every day is a good day&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Try to spend every day meaningfully&amp;rdquo;.
This blog post continues directly from the previous one, so I&amp;rsquo;ll skip the intros. Go read that one for context. Let&amp;rsquo;s just jump into it!
Table of Contents
Runtime Polymorphism Using multi-arity functions Value-based polymorphism with defmulti Comparison to other languages Breaking down what the code means Open to extension Lazy Sequences iterate is also zero-based Standing on the shoulders of giants - using identity Sequence Comprehensions :when and other predefined keyword modifiers Creating Functions The let special form Function composition with comp Recursion Use comment loop?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021Q2: Professional Self Reflection</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/2021-q2-professional-self-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 10:23:18 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/2021-q2-professional-self-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Every Quarter, I try to spend some time on professional self-reflection. It&amp;rsquo;s part of the journey of being aware of what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, why I&amp;rsquo;m doing it, and getting better all the time.
This time, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to blog about it, instead of just putting it in a notebook. Why?
One of the things I want to do is communicate my professional profile better to other people, so this is a way to do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Math Expressions to Hugo Blog - the Shortest Guide Possible</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-add-math-expressions-to-hugo-blog-the-shortest-guide-possible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 12:15:16 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/how-to-add-math-expressions-to-hugo-blog-the-shortest-guide-possible/</guid>
      <description>Want your blog to include Math Expressions, like the Mass–energy equivalence formula?
$$ E=mc^2 $$
Or L&amp;rsquo;Hôpital&amp;rsquo;s rule?
$$ \mathop {\lim }\limits_{x \to c} \frac{{f\left( x \right)}}{{g\left( x \right)}} = \mathop {\lim }\limits_{x \to c} \frac{{f&amp;rsquo;\left( x \right)}}{{g&amp;rsquo;\left( x \right)}} $$
Or Matrix Multiplication?
$$ \begin{pmatrix} 0 &amp;amp; 1 \\ 0 &amp;amp; 0 \end{pmatrix}\begin{pmatrix} 0 &amp;amp; 0 \\ 1 &amp;amp; 0 \end{pmatrix}=\begin{pmatrix} 1 &amp;amp; 0 \\ 0 &amp;amp; 0 \end{pmatrix} $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foray Into Clojure, Part 1: Collections, Conditionals, and Meditations | 隻手声あり、その声を聞け?</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-foray-into-clojure-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 20:39:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-foray-into-clojure-part-1/</guid>
      <description>隻手声あり、その声を聞け? (Two hands clap and there is a sound. What is the sound of one hand?)
- 白隠 慧鶴 (Hakuin Ekaku)
Continuing on the journey of knowledge, I wanted to practice more Clojure. Last time we went over first sections of Learn Clojure: syntax and functions. The main way I learned was by doing the exercises at the bottom of each page. But for the rest of the subjects in the guide, there are no exercises!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foray Into Clojure, Part 0: Setup, syntax, functions</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-foray-into-clojure-part-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 01:03:49 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-foray-into-clojure-part-0/</guid>
      <description>I started this post AFTER starting to work on a Clojure script, when I realized I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel comfortable enough with the language and tools to actually start working on the script. I needed to feel more comfortable before starting to work.
In this post I go over how to setup a basic Clojure development environment and I solve all the exercises from the &amp;ldquo;Learn Clojure&amp;rdquo; guide, with examples and explanations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add EmacsLisp Programs to Emacs - The Hard Way</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/shortest-guide-how-to-add-programs-to-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 15:36:58 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/shortest-guide-how-to-add-programs-to-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Adding EmacsLips programs to extend Emacs&amp;rsquo;s functionality from source is something I&amp;rsquo;ve found non-obvious (had to open multiple tabs for). Today I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to figure it out, and it&amp;rsquo;s actually very simple, so here&amp;rsquo;s the guide:
A - Find the program you want to add In my case, it was &amp;ldquo;Transpose Frame&amp;rdquo; by irie.
I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled across it from this StackExchange answer.
If the program is available on MELPA, you can just add it to the additional-packages list in your .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find the Right Code Knowledge Management Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/code-knowledge-mgmt-swimm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 12:53:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/code-knowledge-mgmt-swimm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swimm.io and Infection Monkey - Open Source Contributor Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/swimming-with-monkeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 12:07:50 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/swimming-with-monkeys/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog #5 | Developing a webpage as an excuse to learn Rust, Yew and WebAssembly</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/dev-log-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 16:09:49 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/dev-log-5/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the rest of the devlogs, you can find them here. You might be missing some context if you don&amp;rsquo;t.
Also, this is an old blogpost about something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually released as part of the project yet. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll finish it but the documentation value is important.
After another successful workshop,
I decided it&amp;rsquo;s time to tackle issue #26 from the project&amp;rsquo;s backlog using rust, Yew, and WebAssembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lectures, COVID-19, and crowd interaction - my DEFCON2020 experience</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/my-2020-defcon-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 01:12:58 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/my-2020-defcon-talk/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave a talk in DefCon SAFEMODE Red Team Village. It was a very interesting and unique experience, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
The talk itself The talk was titled Making Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Accessible and Actionable with Infection Monkey. Watch the recording here:
Lectures, COVID, and crowd interaction Giving a live talk is something I very much enjoy doing. 🎤
Crowd interaction, controlling my voice, gesturing, joking with the audience now and then, answering questions; Honestly, I really like it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog #4 | IT&#39;S ALIIIIIIVE</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/dev-log-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 18:53:26 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/dev-log-4/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the rest of the devlogs, you can find them here. You might be missing some context if you don&amp;rsquo;t.
“The test of the machine is the satisfaction it gives you. There isn&amp;rsquo;t any other test. If the machine produces tranquility it&amp;rsquo;s right. If it disturbs you it&amp;rsquo;s wrong until either the machine or your mind is changed.”
― Robert M. Pirsig, Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance: An Inquiry Into Values</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Open Source on Security - Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/the-impact-of-open-source-on-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 12:07:50 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/the-impact-of-open-source-on-security/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog #3 | I have grown taller from walking with the trees 🌳</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/dev-log-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 18:08:50 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/dev-log-3/</guid>
      <description>“Today I have grown taller from walking with the trees.”
― Karle Wilson Baker
Welcome back to my devlog series, where I discuss the development of make-git-better version 2 - a git CTF challenge. Last time we finished developing a script that automated generating the main git server hook for the CTF.
Today we&amp;rsquo;re automating another big part of the challenge: creating the level browser.
Why do we need a level browser?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>basic-1</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/levels/basic-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 13:04:22 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/levels/basic-1/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we need to delete files, not only add them. But in git deleting a file means add-ing the deletion to the staging area and committing that change.
🧩 Hints Click on hints to reveal them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
