<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>serverless on mrnice.dev</title>
    <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/serverless/</link>
    <description>Recent content in serverless on mrnice.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 20:04:53 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/serverless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We Built a Slack Bot for Valet Parking Services: 🅿️art 3 | The Data</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 20:04:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Part three of the joint project with my incredibly sharp wife, Olga!&#xA;This post is a part of a series, so [check out the entire series for context] (https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/slack/).&#xA;In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into how we&amp;rsquo;ve implemented a Database in our application. The post starts with the design, then moves to implementation of DB connectivity, then the data models themselves, and finally some testing.&#xA;Upfront, we had to decide if we&amp;rsquo;ll choose a relational database or something else - and we decided to go relational.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Built a Slack Bot for Valet Parking Services: 🅿️art 2 | The Logic</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 12:23:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Part two of the joint project with my intelligent and brave wife, Olga!&#xA;This post is a part of a series, so [check out part 1 for context] (../building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp).&#xA;Warning: As our development of this project was a little &amp;ldquo;all over the place&amp;rdquo; as we try to fit it to our busy lives and the Holiday Season, the blog post is a little all over the place as well.&#xA;QoL improvements Slimming down the Docker Image size Adding a test endpoint to the server, to make sure it works Adding basic CI Setting up a local development environment Designing and Building the Bot&amp;rsquo;s Business Logic Let&amp;rsquo;s do some Product - designing the user flows Initial development - design, mocks, stubs Let&amp;rsquo;s do some Development - using Bolt Let&amp;rsquo;s get sidetracked - Web servers, web applications, and WSGI Next up QoL improvements Before moving on the the next big tasks, we wanted to do some small QoL improvements, which we introduced in 3 separate PRs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Built a Slack Bot for Valet Parking Services: 🅿️art 1 | The Start</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 15:18:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp/</guid>
      <description>A joint project with my beautiful wife Olga! &amp;lt;3&#xA;In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll go over how we built a Slack Bot that helped my company manage parking spots.&#xA;Table of Contents Requirements Why do this, the stupid reason Why do this, the real reason Planning Task Management Architecture Working Setting up a working environment Setting up GCP Developing an initial server Containerizing the server Deploying the app to the cloud Connecting the server to Slack What&amp;rsquo;s next?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing AWS Lambda and API Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/testing-aws-lambda-and-api-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 20:15:28 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/testing-aws-lambda-and-api-gateway/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had to fix some bugs in a Python AWS lambda which gets triggered by an API Gateway. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the way that Lambdas work makes you want to develop it badly. So I hope you can use these tips when you develop your Lambdas to do it better.&#xA;I worked on a Python Lambda, so this is what you&amp;rsquo;ll see in this post.&#xA;How to test AWS Lambda + API Gateway successfully Whitebox: Cover the logic in regular unit tests Blackbox: Cover the Gateway API Gateway API Stages Writing the tests Choose which tests you want to run using pytest&amp;rsquo;s -k switch What now How to test AWS Lambda + API Gateway successfully The main thing I found to be useful during the development process of AWS Lambdas that are triggered by a Gateway was testing them automatically, in two ways:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
