<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>musings on mrnice.dev</title>
    <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/musings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in musings on mrnice.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 10:23:18 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021Q2: Professional Self Reflection</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/2021-q2-professional-self-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 10:23:18 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/2021-q2-professional-self-reflection/</guid>
      <description>Every Quarter, I try to spend some time on professional self-reflection. It&amp;rsquo;s part of the journey of being aware of what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, why I&amp;rsquo;m doing it, and getting better all the time.
This time, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to blog about it, instead of just putting it in a notebook. Why?
One of the things I want to do is communicate my professional profile better to other people, so this is a way to do that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Find the Right Code Knowledge Management Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/code-knowledge-mgmt-swimm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 12:53:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/code-knowledge-mgmt-swimm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lectures, COVID-19, and crowd interaction - my DEFCON2020 experience</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/my-2020-defcon-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 01:12:58 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/my-2020-defcon-talk/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave a talk in DefCon SAFEMODE Red Team Village. It was a very interesting and unique experience, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
The talk itself The talk was titled Making Breach &amp;amp; Attack Simulation Accessible and Actionable with Infection Monkey. Watch the recording here:
Lectures, COVID, and crowd interaction Giving a live talk is something I very much enjoy doing. 🎤
Crowd interaction, controlling my voice, gesturing, joking with the audience now and then, answering questions; Honestly, I really like it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Open Source on Security - Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/the-impact-of-open-source-on-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 12:07:50 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/the-impact-of-open-source-on-security/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first Post</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>The blank page So many possibilities, but so much anxiety. How do I make this interesting? Who will even read this? Have I picked the best theme? What should my other posts be? How do I go forward from here? Is this for me, or for you?
Here&amp;rsquo;s a poem about it as well if you thought I wasn&amp;rsquo;t dramatic enough Beating the blank page / Alan j Wright A Battle-Cry for the Brave Young Writer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
