<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cloud on mrnice.dev</title>
    <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cloud on mrnice.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 15:18:40 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mrnice.dev/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We Built a Slack Bot for Valet Parking Services: 🅿️art 1</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 15:18:40 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/building-a-slack-bot-with-python-on-gcp/</guid>
      <description>A joint project with my beautiful wife Olga! &amp;lt;3
In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll go over how we built a Slack Bot that helped my company manage parking spots.
Table of Contents  Requirements  Why do this, the stupid reason Why do this, the real reason  Planning  Task Management Architecture  Working  Setting up a working environment Setting up GCP Developing an initial server Containerizing the server Deploying the app to the cloud Connecting the server to Slack  What&amp;rsquo;s next?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing AWS Lambda and API Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/testing-aws-lambda-and-api-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 20:15:28 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mrnice.dev/posts/testing-aws-lambda-and-api-gateway/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had to fix some bugs in a Python AWS lambda which gets triggered by an API Gateway. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the way that Lambdas work makes you want to develop it badly. So I hope you can use these tips when you develop your Lambdas to do it better.
I worked on a Python Lambda, so this is what you&amp;rsquo;ll see in this post.
 How to test AWS Lambda + API Gateway successfully  Whitebox: Cover the logic in regular unit tests Blackbox: Cover the Gateway API Gateway API Stages Writing the tests Choose which tests you want to run using pytest&amp;rsquo;s -k switch  What now  How to test AWS Lambda + API Gateway successfully The main thing I found to be useful during the development process of AWS Lambdas that are triggered by a Gateway was testing them automatically, in two ways:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
